Objects that are created from a class don't really last forever.
الكائنات التي يتم إنشاؤها من فئة لا تدوم إلى الأبد.
Typically, you'd create an object from a class,
عادة ما يتم إنشاء كائن من فئة،
fill its fields with some values,
وملء خاناته ببعض القيم،
and maybe create another object and fill its fields
ثم إنشاء كائن آخر وملء خاناته بقيم مختلفة،
including every single value stored in those fields.
ويشمل ذلك كل قيمة مخزّنة داخل تلك الخانات.
Typically, that would happen whenever the scope of that object ends.
عادة ما يحدث ذلك عندما ينتهي نطاق ذلك الكائن.
For example here, inside this method,
على سبيل المثال، هنا في هذا الأسلوب،
I've created the variable myItem,
أنشأتُ المتغيّر myItem،
which is an object of the type class Item.
وهو كائن من نوع الفئة Item.
Once this method ends,
بمجرد انتهاء هذا الأسلوب،
this myItem variable doesn't exist anymore,
فإن متغيّر myItem هذا سينتهي من الوجود،
including all the values of all the field inside it.
بما في ذلك كافة القيم الموجودة في جميع الخانات التي في داخله.
This kind of makes sense because you don't really need the values of
هذا منطقي بعض الشيء لأننا لا نحتاج القيم الموجودة
a field inside an object that you can't even access anymore.
في خانة داخل كائن لا يمكننا الوصول إليه بعد الآن.
However, in some rare occasions,
لكن في بعض الحالات النادرة،
you might want to store the value of
قد ترغب في تخزين قيمة خانة محددة حتى لو لم تكن هناك كائنات لتلك الفئة.
In that case, you need to add the keyword static when declaring this field.
في تلك الحالة، عليك إضافة الكلمة الرئيسية static عند تعريف تلك الخانة.
Declaring a field as static means that these values are no longer
تعريف خانة ما على أنها static يعني أن هذه القيم
stored within the object itself but within the class instead.
لم تعد مخزّنة داخل الكائن نفسه وإنما داخل الفئة،
Meaning that all objects of the class will share that same exact value.
بمعنى أن جميع الكائنات لتلك الفئة ستشترك في تلك القيمة المحددة.
And then even if every single object of the class has been destroyed,
بالتالي، حتى لو تم تدمير كافة كائنات تلك الفئة،
the value is still stored within the class.
تبقى تلك القيمة مخزنة داخل الفئة.
If you decide to create a new object of that same class,
إذا قررتم إنشاء كائن جديد لتلك الفئة بنفسها،
then it will end up using the same value that was stored in the class.
فسيستخدم القيمة نفسها المخزنة داخل الفئة في النهاية.
Notice however, that static here doesn't mean that the value doesn't change.
لكن لاحظوا أن static هنا لا تعني أن القيمة لا تتغيّر.
In fact, if that value does change,
في الواقع، إذا تغيّرت تلك القيمة بالفعل،
it will update it in every single object of that class again.
فسيتم تحديثها في كل كائن لتلك الفئة مجدداً.
Now because static fields belong to classes instead of object,
لأن الخانات من نوع static تنتمي إلى الفئات بدلاً من الكائنات،
Java allows you to access a static field directly from
فإن لغة Java تسمح لكم بالوصول إلى حقل من نوع static
the class instead of having to create an object of that class.
من داخل الفئة مباشرة بدلاً من أن يكون عليكم إنشاء كائن من تلك الفئة.
For example here, I can access the power field
هنا مثلاً، يمكنني الوصول إلى خانة power
from the class item directly and set it to a value.
من خلال الفئة Item مباشرة وتحديد قيمة لها.
Let's have a look at a coding example.
لنتناول مثالاً برمجياً.
In this example, I've created a class called Person,
في هذا المثال، أنشأتُ فئة تُدعى Person،
and I'm trying to keep count of every single object that was created from the class.
وأحاول عدّ كل كائن تم إنشاؤه من تلك الفئة.
So, I've added this public int field called count,
لذا، أضفتُ حقلاً من نوع public int يُدعى count،
and inside the constructor,
وداخل المنشئ،
which is just the default constructor,
وهو المنشئ الافتراضي لا أكثر،
I'm incrementing that count by one,
أقوم بزيادة قيمة العدد بواحد،
which means that every time I create a new object of Person,
ما يعني أنه كلما أنشأتُ كائناً جديداً من Person،
it will add one to that count variable.
سيزيد 1 إلى المتغيّر count.
Now if you go to the main method,
والآن إذا انتقلتم إلى الأسلوب الرئيسي،
you could see that I've created this loop that
فيمكنكم أن تروا أنني أنشأتُ هذه الحلقة
starts from zero and counts all the way to 100,
والتي تبدأ من صفر وتواصل العد وصولاً إلى 100.
and inside that loop,
وفي داخل تلك الحلقة،
I'm creating a new instance of that class Person.
أنشئ مثيلاً جديداً من فئة Person تلك.
And every time I create an object,
وكلما أنشئ كائناً،
I print out the count value installed inside it.
أطبع قيمة count المحفوظة داخله.
So when I run this code,
فعندما أنفذ هذا الكود،
I would expect that every time I'm creating a new Person object,
أتوقع أنه كلما أنشئ كائناً من Person،
it's adding one to the counter,
فإن ذلك يزيد 1 إلى العداد.
and by the time we reach to the hundredth Person,
وعندما نصل إلى الكائن رقم 100 من Person،
the count value would be 100.
ستكون قيمة count عندئذ مساوية لـ100.
So I'm expecting to see the numbers between one and 100.
لذا، أتوقع أن أرى الأعداد بين 1 و100.
However, if I do run this code,
لكن إذا نفّذتُ هذا الكود بالفعل،
it seems like I'm just getting a bunch of ones,
فيبدو أنني أحصل على مجموعة من الآحاد فحسب،
which means that this count variable is not being updated at all.
ما يعني أن متغيّر count هذا لا يخضع للتحديث مطلقاً.
The explanation for that is pretty simple.
وتفسير ذلك بسيط جداً.
If we go back to the Person class,
إذا عدنا إلى فئة Person،
you'd notice that I haven't declared this count variable as static,
فستلاحظون أنني لم أعرّف متغيّر count على أنه من نوع static،
which means that it belongs to the object not the class.
وهذا يعني أنه تابع للكائن وليس للفئة.
And because I'm creating a new object every time,
ولأنني أقوم بإنشاء كائن جديد في كل مرة،
it means I'm creating a new variable called count and I'm only adding one to it.
فهذا معناه أنني أنشئ متغيّراً جديداً اسمه count وأضيف إليه 1 فقط.
So every single object would have its own count variable that has the value one.
فسيكون لكل كائن متغيّر count خاص به يحمل القيمة 1.
However, if I do add the static keyword to our count variable here,
لكن إذا أضفتُ كلمة static إلى متغيّر count هنا،
this means that this variable now belongs to the class rather than the object.
فهذا معناه أن هذا المتغيّر ينتمي الآن إلى الفئة بدلاً من الكائن.
And every time I'm calling the constructor,
وكلما أستدعي المنشئ،
it's adding one to the same variable count.
يضيف 1 إلى المتغيّر count نفسه.
So if I run this now,
فإذا نفّذتُ هذا الآن،
I should get all the numbers between one and 100 like I expected earlier.
ينبغفي أن أحصل على كافة الأعداد بين 1 و100 كما توقعتُ منذ قليل.
Counting the instances that were created from a class is one
عدّ المثيلات التي تم إنشاؤها من فئة ما
of the very common use cases for using the static keyword.
هو واحد من أكثر الاستخدامات شيوعاً لكلمة static.
So why don't you go ahead and try this yourself as well.
فما رأيكم أن تجرّبوا هذا بأنفسكم أيضاً؟